Guide to the George Rosen Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Rosen papers
1912-1978
MS 862
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
15.25
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, photographs, and other materials documenting the professional and scholarly career of George Rosen. Also included are files from the American Public Health Association and editorial files of the American Journal of Public Health and Ciba Symposia. Forms part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Rosen, George, 1910-1977
Conditions Governing Access
Student recommendations and evaluations in Series V, Box 36 are restricted until January 2053 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Beate Caspari-Rosen, 1978-1982, and 1991. Transfer from the Yale University Historical Medical Library, 1981, and the Section of the History of Medicine, Yale University School of Medicine, 1991.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. Correspondence. II. American Public Health Association Files. III. Subject Files. IV. Writings. V. Yale University Files. VI. Personal Papers and Photographs.
Scope and Contents
The collection reflects the professional career of George Rosen and includes correspondence between Rosen and many of the major researchers in the field of public health and history of medicine. The papers also consist of editorial files from American Journal of Public Health, Ciba Symposia, and Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences and subject files documenting the American Public Health Association. Drafts and supporting correspondence and research files for his writings document Rosen's scholarly contributions.
Biographical / Historical
George Rosen was born June 23, 1910 in Brooklyn, New York. He was educated in the public schools of New York City before attending the City College of New York, where he graduated in 1930 with a Bachelor of Science degree. Rosen acquired his M.D. from the University of Berlin in 1935. At the suggestion of Henry Sigerist, Rosen wrote a historical dissertation on the reception and influence in Europe of the research of William Beaumont, the American physician-physiologist. This work sparked a lifelong interest in the history of medicine.
With the rise of the Nazis, Rosen returned to the United States soon after obtaining his degree. He interned at Beth-El Hospital before starting a private practice in ophthalmology and otolaryngology. In 1941, he gave up his medical practice to work in the New York City Department of Public Health as a clinic physician in the Bureau of Tuberculosis. He later became a district health officer and then Director of the Bureau of Health Education.
While working in these capacities, Rosen also continued his research, writing, and studies. In the years 1938-1944, he edited the journal Ciba Symposia with his wife, Beate Caspari-Rosen, and he published his first monograph, The History of Miners' Diseases: A Medical and Social Interpretation, in 1944. In 1941, he began graduate studies in sociology at Columbia University, where he was awarded a Ph.D. in 1947.
Rosen served in World War II as a medical intelligence officer in the Division of Preventative Medicine within the Surgeon General's office. Shortly after the war, he participated in the interrogation of Nazi generals in London as a translator.
Upon returning from Europe after the war, Rosen resumed his public health career and his studies at Columbia University, where he obtained a master's degree in public health in 1950. Also in that year, Rosen was appointed director of the Division of Health Education and Preventative Services of the Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, while he concurrently held the position of professor of public health education in the School of Public Health and Administrative Medicine at Columbia. In 1969, he devoted himself full-time to scholarly pursuits, joining the Department of History of Science and Medicine at Yale University, where he also taught courses in Yale College, the Graduate School, and the School of Medicine.
George Rosen was best known for the breadth and volume of his scholarly work which covered many topics and time periods. He published eleven books and over two hundred articles on topics relating to the history of medicine and public health. He also served as editor of the American Journal of Public Health (1957-1973) and Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences (1946-1952), which he also helped to incorporate.
Rosen and his wife Beate met at the University of Berlin while both were medical students, and they were married in 1933. They had two children, Susan and Peter. George Rosen died on July 27, 1977 in Oxford, England.
American journal of public health (New York, N.Y.: 1912); Ciba Foundation symposium; Journal of the history of medicine and allied sciences; Public health; Educators; Physicians; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Ackerknecht, Erwin, 1880-1960; Caspari-Rosen, Beate, 1910-; Falk, I. S. (Isidore Sydney), 1899-1984; Falk, Leslie A.; Fulton, John F.; Galdston, Iago, 1895-; Hartung, Edward; Jarcho, Saul; King, Lester S. (Lester Snow), 1908-; Leikind, Morris C. (Morris Cecil), 1905-1976; Lesky, Erna, 1911-; Miller, Genevieve; Paul, John R. (John Rodman), 1893-1971; Roemer, Milton Irwin, 1916-2001; Rosen, George, 1910-1977; Schuman, Henry; Shepherd, Michael, 1923-1995; Sheps, Cecil G. (Cecil George), 1913-2004; Shryock, Richard Harrison, 1893-1972; Sigerist, Henry E. (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957; Stanton, Madeline E. (Madeline Earle); Stevenson, Lloyd G., 1918-; Sussman, George D., 1943-; Tempkin, Owsei; Tjomsland, Anne, 1880-; Urdang, George, 1882-1960; Wangensteen, Owen H. (Owen Harding), 1898-1981; Weiner, Dora B.; Yankauer, Alfred; Zilboorg, Gregory, 1890-1959; American Public Health Association; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Epidemiology and Public Health
- Correspondence, 1933-1978; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged alphabetically, the series consists primarily of George Rosen's professional correspondence with historians, physicians, sociologists, public health officials, publishers, and professional organizations. The majority of the correspondence is incoming, although there are many letters written by Rosen in the files.
  Rosen's correspondence with fellow historians of medicine and science, public health administrators and educators, and physicians provides documentation on the intellectual discourse in the respective disciplines during the middle part of the twentieth century. The series includes substantial amount of correspondence with Erwin H. Ackerknecht, Isidore S. Falk, Leslie A. Falk, John F. Fulton, Iago Galdston, Edward F. Hartung, Saul Jarcho, Lester S. King, Morris C. Leikind, Erna Lesky, Genevieve Miller, John Rodman Paul, Milton I. Roemer, Henry Schuman, Michael Shepherd, Cecil Sheps, Richard Shryock, Henry Sigerist, Madeline Stanton, Lloyd G. Stevenson, George Sussman, Owsei Tempkin, Anna Tjomsland, George Urdang, Owen Wangensteen, Dora B. Weiner, Alfred Yankauer, and Gregory Zilboorg.
  The series also includes eight folders of letters between Rosen and his wife, Beate Caspari- Rosen. The correspondence spans the years 1936-1961 and documents their professional relationship, Rosen's military service in World War II, and personal and family matters, among other things.
  - A (General) (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Acheson, Roy M., 1969-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ackerknecht, Erwin, 1942-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    General note
    See also: Series III, folder 50
  - American Philosophical Society, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Psychiatric Association, 1966-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B (General) (Box 1, Folder 10-15)
  - Bailey, Doyne, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ballester, Luis Garcia, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ballinger, Walter F., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barshcel, H. J.
    See: Series III, folder 53
  - Baumgartner, Leona, 1947-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bean, William B., 1950-1976 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Beck, Ann, 1973-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bell, Whitfield J., 1949-1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bellis, Elizabeth, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Beloff, Jerry, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Benedikt, Lucie, 1969-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Beneson, Abram S., undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Benison, Saul, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Benton, Edward, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bett, Walter R., 1939-1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bilebof, Louise F., 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Bishop, George W., 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Blake, John B., 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bloch, Harry, 1953-1976 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Born, Wolfgang
    See: Series III, folder 54
  - Boudreau, Frank G., 1947-1963 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bowden, Mary Ellen, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bowers, John Z., 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Bozof, Richard, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bradnan, William Andrew, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Brand, Jeanne L., 1961-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Breslow, Lester, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Brewer, A. D.
    See: Series III, folder 55
  - Brieger, Gert H., 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Broughton, Philip S., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Brown, H. W., 1948-1953 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Brown, Virginia, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Buchanan, Beverly, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Bynum, William, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - C (General) (Box 2, Folder 48-51)
  - Carlson, Eric T., 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Caspari, Flora, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Caspari-Rosen, Beate, 1936-1961 (Box 3, Folder 54-61)
  - Castiglioni, Arthur, 1943-1950 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Cave, Carolyn, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Clarke, Edwin, 1949-1977 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Cohart, Edward M., 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Cohen, I. Bernard, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Comer, James P., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Concordia Publishing House (Luther's Works), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Conn, Harold J.
    See: Series III, folder 57
  - Cook, Charles D., 1968-1976 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Cortes, Kathleen F., 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Crosby, Al, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Curran, William J.
    See: Series II, folder 11
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - D (General) (Box 3, Folder 73-76)
  - Davis, Michael W., 1940-1969 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Debus, Allen G., 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Denues, A.R. Taylor, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Devries, Louis, 1944-1975 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Dewey, Nicholas, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Diepgen, Paul, 1946-1959 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Drachman, Theodore S., 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Duffy, John, 1969-1977 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Dyos, H. J., 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - E (General) (Box 4, Folder 86-87)
  - Ebbert, Arthur, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Eckman, James R., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Egan, Gisela, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Ely, Barbara S., 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Emerson, William R., 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Encyclopedia of Bioethics, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Epstein, Sherrie S., 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Erwin, Robert, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - F (General) (Box 4, Folder 96-99)
  - Falk, Isidore S., 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Falk, Leslie A., 1948-1976 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Fitz, Reginald H., 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Forbes, Thomas R., 1969-1977 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Francis, H. W. S., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Freeman, Howard E., 1962-1976 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Frost, Kate, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Fulton, John F., 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - G (General) (Box 5, Folder 108-114)
  - Galdston, Iago, 1942-1960 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Gari, Lydia, 1962-1971 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Gebhard, Bruno, 1946-1976 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    See also: Series III, folder 62
  - Glass, William H., 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Glenn, William W. L., 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Greenwald, Isidor, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Greenwood Press, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Gruenberg, Ernest, 1963-1976 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Gundry, L. D., 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Gussow, Zachary, 1968-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - H (General) (Box 5, Folder 125-129)
  - Harper and Row, 1965-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Hartung, Edward F., 1939-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Heischkel-Artelt, Edith, 1950-1976 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Henne, H., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Hesse, Friedrich M., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Hiscock, Ira V., 1949-1973 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Hodgkinson, Ruth, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Huxley, Matthew, 1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - I (General) (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - International Children's Centre, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Iuoto, Mark, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - J (General) (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Jacob, H. E.
    See: Series III, folder 66
  - Jarcho, Saul, 1945-1977 (Box 6, Folder 142-143)
  - Jekel, James, 1969-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Johnson, Eric, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Jonas, Steven, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - K (General) (Box 6, Folder 147-150)
  - Kabara, John J., 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Kaempffert, Waldemar, 1944-1949 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Kahn, Fritz, 1938-1945 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Kelly, George Armstrong, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Kerr, John W., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - King, Lester S., 1968-1977 (Box 6, Folder 156-157)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., 1938-1973 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Koelbing, Huldrych M., 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - Koslow, Arnold, 1968, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Koslow, Susan [daughter]
    See: Series VI, folder 2
  - Koudelka, Janey, 1956-1977 (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - Kowal, Areta O., 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Kringlen, Einar, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Krogman, Wilton M.
    See: Series III, folder 68
  - Kuna, Ralph, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Kunitz, Stephen J., 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - L (General) (Box 7, Folder 166-169)
  - La Berge, Ann, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Lanza, Anthony J., 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Leibowitz, Joshua O., 1957, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Leikind, Morris C., 1939-1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 173-174)
  - Lerner, Raymond, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Lesky, Erna, 1955-1977 (Box 7, Folder 176-177)
  - Levine, Sol, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Levitin, Howard, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Lewis, Evelyn, 1963, 1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Lieberman, Janet, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Lilienfield, Abraham M.
    See: Series II, folder 13
  - Lindenlaub, Dieter, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Link, Eugene P., 1948-1949, 1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Lippard, Vernon, 1963-1976 (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Littman, Robert J., 1976 (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - Loehr, William M., 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Lopez, Jose M., 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Lubove, Roy, 1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Lundy, John S., 1950 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Luoto, Mark H., 1973-1974, undated (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Lyons, Albert S., 1969-1977 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Lyskanowski, Marlin, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - M (General) (Box 8, Folder 193-198)
  - MacKinney, Loren C., 1942-1954, undated (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - MacLennan, A., 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Malamud, Enrique, 1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Mann, Gunter, 1970-1977 (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - Marti-Ibanez, Felix, 1942-1972 (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - McCollum, Robert W., 1969-1970, undated (Box 8, Folder 204)
  - McConnell, Harry M., 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 205)
  - McEwan, Peter J. M., 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 206)
  - McKeown, Thomas, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 207)
  - Mellizo, Felipe, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - Miles, Wyndham, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - Miller, Genevieve, 1941-1971 (Box 8, Folder 210)
  - Milligan, Bob, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 211)
  - Millman, Michael, 1973-1974, undated (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - Monahan, James, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Montagu, M. F. Ashley
    See: Series III, folder 73
  - Montague, Joel, 1969-1976 (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - Mora, George, 1961-1976, undated (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - Mostow, Evelyn, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Mullins, Richard J., 1977 (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - N (General) (Box 9, Folder 218-219)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 220-221)
  - Neaman, Judith, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 222)
  - Niebyl, Peter H., 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 223)
  - Nuland, Sherman B., 1976 (Box 9, Folder 224)
  - O (General) (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - Oguni, Shiro, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - Oppenheimer, Ernst, 1939-1949 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    See also: Series III, folders 76-77
  - Osterberg, Eric R., 1963 (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - Ostfeld, Adrian, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 229)
  - P (General) (Box 9, Folder 230-232)
  - Pagel, Walter, 1937-1938, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - Pagliard, Harold E., 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 234)
  - Paine, Leslie, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 235)
  - Paul, John Rodman, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 236)
  - Perlin, Seymour, 1968-1971, undated (Box 9, Folder 237)
  - Perry, W. Pearl, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 238)
  - Peter, William W., 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 239)
  - Pogo, Alexander, 1942-1947 (Box 9, Folder 240)
  - Price, Bruce, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 241)
  - Price, Derek de Solla, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 242)
  - Priedel, Herbert, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 243)
  - Q (General) (Box 10, Folder 244)
  - Quem, Jacques, 1969-1976 (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - R (General) (Box 10, Folder 246-250)
  - Randar, Mary, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - Ransom, John E.
    See: Series III, folder 80
  - Reich, Warren T., 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - Reverby, Susan, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - Richard, Frank F., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 254)
  - Richards, Dickinson, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 255)
  - Risse, Guenter B., 1971-1977, undated (Box 10, Folder 256)
  - Robinson, Victor
    See: Series III, folder 81
  - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 257)
  - Roder, Paul W.
    See: Series III, folders 82-84
  - Roemer, Milton I., 1941-1976, undated (Box 10, Folder 258)
  - Rosen, Peter [son]
  - Rosenberg, Charles, 1971-1976 (Box 10, Folder 259)
  - Rosenkrantz, Barbara, 1973-1977 (Box 10, Folder 260)
  - S (General) (Box 10, Folder 261-268)
  - Sabelle, Verna, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 269)
  - Sadle, Blair, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 270)
  - Sayers, R. R., 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 271)
  - Schmitt, Mary Margaret, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 272)
  - Schneider, Howard Lawrence, 1962-1971 (Box 11, Folder 273)
  - Schullian, Dorothy M., 1971-1977 (Box 11, Folder 274)
  - Schuman, Henry, 1939-1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 275)
    See also: Series III, folders 118-119
  - Schwab, John, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 276)
  - Seeger, Raymond, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 277)
  - Segall, Ascher, 1968-1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 278)
  - Segall, Harold, 1948-1949, 1970-1976 (Box 11, Folder 279)
  - Shepherd, Michael, 1970-1977 (Box 11, Folder 280-281)
  - Sheps, Cecil G., 1948-1973 (Box 11, Folder 282)
  - Shryock, Richard H., 1939-1953, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 283-284)
  - Sigerist, Henry E., 1933-1956 (Box 11, Folder 285-287)
  - Sigman, Harvey, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 288)
  - Silver, George, 1962-1976 (Box 11, Folder 289)
  - Silvers, Robert B., 1972 (Box 11, Folder 290)
  - Singer, Charles, 1942-1951 (Box 11, Folder 291)
  - Slade, Valeda, 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 292)
  - Smith, Marjorie, 1953-1958 (Box 11, Folder 293)
  - Solis-Cohen, Solomon, 1941-1942, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 294)
  - Spector, Benjamin, 1940-1957 (Box 12, Folder 295)
  - Spencer, Robert F.
    See: Series III, folder 88
  - Spies, Tom D., 1950 (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - Stanton, Madeline, 1947-1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 297-298)
    See: Series III, folders 118-119
    See: Series III, folder 89
  - Starr, Joseph, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 299)
  - Starr, Louis, 1964-1976 (Box 12, Folder 300)
  - Stevenson, Isobel
    See: Series III, folder 90
  - Stevenson, Lloyd G., 1949-1975 (Box 12, Folder 301-303)
  - Steward, Ileen E., 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 304)
  - Susser, Mervyn, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 305)
  - Sussman, George, 1969-1975 (Box 12, Folder 306-307)
  - T (General) (Box 12, Folder 308-309)
  - Tellmadge, G. Kasten
    See: Series III, folder 92
  - Tempkin, Lilian, 1968-1971 (Box 12, Folder 310)
  - Tempkin, Owsei, 1938-1973 (Box 12, Folder 311)
  - Terris, Milton O., 1948-1976 (Box 12, Folder 312)
  - Theodorides, Jean, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 313)
  - Thomson, Elizabeth H., 1954-1973 (Box 12, Folder 314)
  - Tjomsland, Anna, 1938-1948 (Box 12, Folder 315)
    See also: Series III, folder 93
  - Toledo, Alice, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 316)
  - Toorock, Frances, 1962-1969 (Box 12, Folder 317)
  - Trantow, Don J., 1970 (Box 12, Folder 318)
  - Truelson, Stanley D., 1969-1976 (Box 12, Folder 319)
  - U (General) (Box 13, Folder 320)
  - Underwood, E. Ashworth, 1945-1951 (Box 13, Folder 321)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1967-1968, undated (Box 13, Folder 322)
  - University of Texas Medical School, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 323)
  - Urdang, George, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 324)
  - V (General) (Box 13, Folder 325)
  - Veith, Ilza, 1952, 1969-1977 (Box 13, Folder 326)
  - Vescia, Fernando G., 1977 (Box 13, Folder 327)
  - Violich, Francis
    See: Series III, folder 95
  - Viseltear, Arthur, 1964-1975 (Box 13, Folder 328)
  - Vogel, Morris J., 1976 (Box 13, Folder 329)
  - W (General) (Box 13, Folder 330-333)
  - Walsh, Anthony, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - Wangensteen, Owen, 1959-1976 (Box 13, Folder 335-338)
  - Watson, Neale, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 339)
  - Watson, Robert I., 1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 340)
  - Weiner, Dora B., 1969-1977, undated (Box 14, Folder 341)
  - Whittaker, Christine, 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 342)
  - Wilde, Anne, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 343)
  - Wilson, Leonard G., 1970-1977 (Box 14, Folder 344)
  - Wilson, W. J.
    See: Series III, folder 97
  - Winslow, Charles-Edward Amory, 1948-1952, undated (Box 14, Folder 345)
  - Wolff, George, 1938-1949 (Box 14, Folder 346)
  - Wolff, Werner
    See: Series III, folder 98
  - Woodford, Leonard W., 1970-1976 (Box 14, Folder 347)
  - Wright, Nicholas H.
    See: Series II, folder 14
  - Wylie, Murray
    See: Series II, folder 15
  - Y (General) (Box 14, Folder 348)
  - Yankauer, Alfred, 1969-1975 (Box 14, Folder 349)
    See also: Series II, folders 16-17
  - Z (General) (Box 14, Folder 350)
  - Zilboorg, Gregory, 1941-1956 (Box 14, Folder 351)
  - Zolyomi, Norbert Duka, 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 352)
  - Unidentified (Box 14, Folder 353)
- American Public Health Association Files, 1916-1978; Series II
  The series is arranged alphabetically and documents George Rosen's service to the American Public Health Association, particularly his contributions to the American Journal of Public Health. Rosen began serving on the editorial board of the journal in 1948 and became editor in 1957, a post he held until 1973. The files on the journal consist of correspondence, minutes, reports, and contributed manuscripts, primarily from the last five years of his tenure as editor.
  Other general files documenting the association include correspondence, pamphlets and other printed matter, and topical files. Seven folders of material on the Statistics Section comprise a substantial portion of the series.
  Photographs taken at the annual conference of the association from 1928 to 1937 can be found in Series VI.
  - American Journal of Public Health
    - Centennial issue, 1964, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - A-Z (General), 1971-1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 2-8)